GABRIEL DAVILA

DEVELOPER FRONTEND WEB





🎓 630-864-0607 | 💟 gdavila0819@gmail.com | 🖨 gabedavila.netlify.app |



PROFILE



I am a qualified and professional frontend developer with 3 years of programming experience, with 1 year of professional experience working

create high-quality applications with a great user experience. I am

continuously learning and developing my skills further while seeking

with clients. Creatively driven with a endless curiosity, I use my skills to

github.com/GabrielJDavila

SKILLS

- ReactJS
- Javascript
- CSS
- HTML
- Firebase
- Git/Github
- Figma
- Visual Studio Code

- UX/UI Design
- Wireframing
- Bootstrap
- APIs

EXPERIENCE

meaningful work to create a positive impact.

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Self-employed

2022 - Present

- Website and web application design for small businesses
- · Utilized ReactJS, Firebase, JS, CSS, and HTML, Git
- Created a 'Team Notes' app for a fitness studio, professional website for a cleaning business, among other projects.

FREELANCE HEALTH & FITNESS WRITER

Self-employed

2020 - 2023

- As an expert in fitness, researched and wrote articles that drew attention to business/product.
- Created graphic and video content for business's social media platforms (Instagram, YouTube). Wrote the copy for social media posts.

FITNESS COACH

Various

2016 - 21 Planet Fitness | 2017 - 23 self-employed | 2020 - 23 H4 Training

- · Various work environments: commercial gyms, high-end studios, and clients' homes.
- Provided outstanding customer service and experience.
- Wrote articles, kept website content maintained for high-end studio.
- Built web application for small business (Team Notes App).

PROJECT SAMPLES

H4 Team Notes: Live | GitHub

- Team notes app for fitness studio. Users can sign up and login, create/update/delete notes, and add clients to the database.
- Tools: React Router, Firebase, HTML, CSS

M&G Business Budget Tracker: Live | GitHub

- Budget tracker built for a small cleaning business. Add/delete income & expenses, and a dashboard renders total income, expenses, and profits.
- Tools: React Router, Firebase, HTML, CSS

EDUCATION

COLLEGE: Waubonsee Community College Associate of Kinesiology August 2014 - 2016

TEAM TREEHOUSE

Frontend Web Development Track May 2021 - December 2022

SCRIMBA FRONTEND BOOTCAMP

January 2023 - Present